Guide to the Hoover Institution Archives Photograph Card Catalog
Hoover Institution Archives
- Vardy, Alexander Collection, undated; 5 prints / 1 envelope (Box 91014 - Photo file)
  4 prints depicting Alexander and Nomi Vardy and others upon the 10th anniversary of Nomi Vardy's work at Radio Liberty; and 1 print depicting Soviet philosophers at the 14th International Philosophy Congress in Vienna, Austria.
- Vatcher, William H. Jr. Collection, 93 photographs / 11 original cartoons / 17 slide cartridges / 4 envelopes (Box 53006 - 10.A-V, 8.28)
  - 2 prints of W.H. Vatcher in Japan, 1952; 13 prints of W.H. Vatcher's trip on the Trans-Siberian Railroad, 1962, undated (Folder A)
  - 32 prints of American propaganda warfare, Pacific theatre, World War, 1939-1945 (Folder B)
  - 46 prints of combat areas, American forces, and Japanese prisoners in the Pacific theatre, World War, 1939-1945 (Folder C)
  - 11 original cartoons on South African politics, undated (Folder mD)
  - 17 slide cartridges with pictures of Africa. Notebook with list of slides is in the box, undated (Folder 18)
- Veneman, John G. Collection, 37 prints / 6 envelopes (Box 82059 - Photo file)
  - 2 prints of John Veneman, undated (Folder A)
  - 12 prints of Nelson Rockefeller including 2 depicting him speaking before an audience; 1 print of Nelson Rockefeller with his wife; 3 prints of Nelson Rockefeller with John Veneman; 2 prints of Nelson Rockefeller with Robert Dole and 1 print of Nelson Rockefeller with Elliot Richardson, 1975-1976 (Folder mB)
  - 7 prints of John Veneman including 4 depicting him with President Gerald Ford, Ronald Reagan, Spencer Williams, Bob Monagan, Rogers Morton; 1 print of John Veneman with Mrs. Nelson Rockefeller, 1975; 1 print of John Veneman with Stuart Spencer at a reception for Russian and American atholetes at the State Department, 1976; and 1 print of John Veneman in a meeting with William Coleman, Majorie Lynch, John B. Rhinelander and Nelson Rockefeller, 1975 (Folder mC)
  - 1 print depicting Richard Nixon speaking at the Republican National Convention, and signed by him commending John Veneman for his outstanding contribution to the success of the Convention, 1976 (Folder mD)
  - 9 prints of John Veneman with other unidentified individuals, and 1 print depicting him with another person, 1971 (Box E)
  - 3 prints of unidentified individuals, undated (Folder mF)
- Vesselago (George M.) Collection, undated; 50 prints / 1 envelope (Box 75062 - 10.A-V)
  50 prints collected by G.M. Vesselago, Imperial Russian Naval officer, depicting scenes in Siberia, Mexico, and the U.S.
- Voegelin, Eric Collection, 19 prints / 5 envelopes (Box 75070 - 10.A-V)
  - 2 passport photos, 1948 and 1963; and 1 print of Eric Voegelin in August 1966 (Folder A)
  - 4 prints of Eric Voegelin and other participants of a conference organized by the intitut fur Politische Wissenschaft in Salzburg, Austria, August 2, 1962 (Folder B)
  - 1 print of Eric Voegelin speaking at a conference organized by the Istituto Accademico di Roma in Roma, Italy, October 4, 1968 (Folder C)
  - 9 prints of Eric Voegelin at the University of Augsburg, West Germany, upon receiving an honorary degree, May 13, 1981 (Box D)
  - 2 prints of Eric Voegelin in Munich, West Germany, upon receiving the city's gold medal "Munchen leuchtet - Den Freund Munchens,", May 20, 1981 (Box E)
- Von Mohrenschildt (Dimitri) Collection, 1900-1918; 37 prints / 1 envelope (Box 71071 - 10.A-V)
  37 photos of the Romanov family before and during the Russian revolution.
- Von Wiegand, Karl Henry Collection, 3,373 prints, 17 negatives, 5 drawings, 1 plate glass negative / 43 envelopes (Box 75092 - 10.A-V)
- Vrangel', Baron Petr Collection, circa 2000 prints, 16 glass plates / 5 oversize boxes, 2 manuscript boxes (Box 27001 - 10.A-V)
  - Album: "Soiuz Invalidov v Bolgarii", (File 120), Album: "Kubanskoe Generala M.V. Alekseeva, Voennoe Uchilishche" (File 121), 1920s (Folder 169)
  - Album: "Russkaia Armiia v Gallipoli, 1921" (File 122), Album: "Russkaia Armiia na Balkanakh", 1920's (File 123), Album: "Konstantinovskoe Voennoe Uchilishche, 1920-1922" (File 124), Album: "Russkaia Armiia v Servbii", 1920's (File 125), Album "Russkaia Armiia v Bolgarii", 1920's (File 126) (Folder 170)
  - Album: "Gruppa Kornilovskago Voennago uchilishcha v Pernike", 1925 (File 127), Album: "Gruppa Kornilovskago Voennago Uchilishcha v Vil'tse", 1927-1928 (File 128), Album: "L'Armee Russe au Travail dans les Balkans", 1922-1923 (File 129), Album: same as above, 1924 (File 130), Album: L'Armee Russe en Exil, 1926 (File 131), Album: "Na dobruiu pamiat'". Detskii priiut Rossiiskago Obshchestva krasnago Kresta v Sofii, 1925 (File 132), Miscellaneous prints related to Civil War, 1918-1919 (?) (Folder 171)
    Includes Kiev, Rostov, KHar'kov, Taganrog, Ekaterinoslav, Novorossiisk and Kursk Front. Prints depict airplanes, armored trains, tanks and other vehicles; navy vessels, river flotilla; group photographs of White Army in action and on parade; female volunteers; Bolshevik atrocities; Gens. Kornilov, Mai-Maevskii, Shkuro, Popov, Semiletov, Konovodov. File (133), Photographs depicting funeral of Baron Petr Vrangel' in Brussels, April 28, 1928. (File 134).
  - Glass plates and prints representing Hetman Skoropadskii and miscellaneous scenes of the Ukraine, 1918 (Folder 172-173)
    Includes group photographs of "KHlebobory" Party delegates from KHerson, KHar'kov, Ekaterinoslav, Poltava and Kursk. (File 251).
  - Miscellaneous prints related to "Zapiski" of Baron Petr Vrangel' (Folder 174)
    Includes newspaper clippings. Prints depict White Army units in action; group photographs including Gens. Denikin, Vrangel' and SHatilov; Trotsky and Kamenev on military parade in Moscow and Petrograd; TSaritsyn and Sevastopol'; Gens. Kornilov, Erdeli, SHkuro, Ulagai, Drozdovskii, Kel'chevskii, Kazanovich, Ungern-SHternberg, Sidorin, Kutepov, Vitkovskii, Lukomskii, Mamontov, Bogaevskii, IUzefovich, Naumenko, Gusel'shchikov, Kel'chevskii, Dukhonin and staff, Admiral Kolchak, Ataman Semenov and Grand Duke Dimitrii Pavlovich. Also L. Bych, Revoliutsionnyi Polk Glavkoverkha Sorokina and partisans of Gen. SHkuro. (P.W. 2), Album: "Donskoi Korpus svoemu Glavnokomanduiushchemu v Pamiat' Prebyvaniia na o. Lemnose, 1920-1921" (P.W. 9), Album: "Tersko-Astrakhanskii kazachii polk za-granitsei", 1925 (P.W. 10)
  - Album: "Glavnokomanduiushchemu i Pochetnomu Predsedateliu Obshchestva, Zagrebskii Otdel Gallipoliitsev, 17-X-26" (P.W. 11) Album: "Pskovskie Leib Draguny, Mitavskie Gusary i SHtab 2-oi Kav. Brigady Svoemu Orli...Baronu P.N. Vrangeliu podnosiat vospominanie o sluzhbe v...Pogranichnoi Strazhi Korolevstva S.KH.S.", 1921-1922 (P.W. 12), Album: "Morskoi Korpus v Bizerte", 1920's (P.W. 13), Album: "Nashemu Vozhdiu Generalu Baronu P.N. Vrangeliu bezzavetno predannyi Krymskii Kadet", 1920's (P.W. 14) (Folder 175)
- Wainwright, W. A. Collection, undated; 2 prints / 1 envelope (Box XX528 - 10.A-V)
  2 prints by W. A. Wainwright including an aerial view of Iwo Jima, and a print of the dedication of a memorial flagstaff on Iwo Jima by U.S. troops.
- Wales (Nym) Collection, 1268 photos, 17 photo postcards, 9 copies of printed photos, 4 photo bookplates, and 205 negative strips, 3 albums / 33 envelopes, 1 album box. (Box 58002 - 10.A-V)
- Wallgren, Albian A. Collection, 1918; 1 cartoon (Box m50017 - 10.A-V dr. 5)
  An original cartoon by Albian A. Wallgren, relating to the A.E.F. in France during World War I.
- Warren, Gerald L. Collection, 300 prints, 1 postcard / 31 envelopes (Box 80062 - 10.A-V)
- Washington, Harold George Collection, 1918-20; prints and post cards / 1 manuscript box (Box 61021 - 9.12)
  Photographs and post cards depicting social conditions, railroads and Allied troops in Siberia and Manchuria during the Russian Revolution, and buildings and war damage in France.
- Watkins (James T.) Collection, 12 prints / 1 envelope (Box 71040 - 10 A-V Envelope mA)
  12 photos of aerial scenes of Kure, Japan, December 1945; Nagasaki, Japan, September and December 1945; and Hiroshima, Japan December 1945. Also include 1 photo of a sunken battleship in Japanese harbor, 1945.
- Watkins, James T. Collection, undated; 1 folder / 3 prints (Box 71040 - 10.A-V mA)
  3 identical prints of Lyndon B. Johnson
- Wayne, Roy E. Collection, circa 1918-1919; 11 prints / 1 envelope (Box 71072 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  Depicts social conditions and refugees in Yugoslavia, Russia and Turkey.
- Webster (James B.) Collection, 1 envelope / 28 prints (Box 70027 - 10 A-V)
  - 28 photos of scenes of the Chinese Revolution and of daily life and cultural sites in China, 1911-1912
  - 3 mounted photos, 9 oversize, 4 prints), undated (Folder m*)
- Wedemeyer, Albert C. Collection, circa 2565 prints / 2 albums, 72 envelopes (Box 83007 - 10.A-V)
- Wesley, Edgar Bruce Collection, 1980; 3 prints / 1 envelope (Box 82092 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  3 prints depicting Edgar B. Wesley with Wilbur and Marion Murra.
- Wheeler, Raymond A. Collection, 730 prints, 6 albums / 26 envelopes, 3 album boxes (Box 78062 - Photo file)
- Whitcomb, John M. Collection, 50 prints / 3 envelopes (Box 80170 - 10.A-V)
  - Depicts communist leaders from various countries, 1904-1939 (Folder A-B)
    Includes a number of photographs of delegates to congresses of the Communist International.
  - 2 prints depicting the house where Karl Marx lived in London (Folder C)
- White, Geoffrey Collection, 1959; 11 slides (Box 78106 - Cassette drawer)
  Posters and stickers relating to socialist election campaign in Berkeley, California.
- Whitehead (James H.) Collection, 1918-1919; 400 photos / 1 envelope and 2 albums (Box 74029-10 A-V)
  About 400 photos and postcards, depicting activities of members of the A.E.F. Siberia and the Russian Railway Service Corps. Includes photos of Gen. W.S. Graves, Czech and Russian forces, the living quarters of Nicholas II at Ekaterinburg, etc.
- Whiting, Charles J. Collection, 1955; 1 framed photograph / 1 album box (Box 74100 - 8M.02 Album fA)
  1 print of Admiral A. A. Burke.
- Wilbur, Ray Lyman Collection, 38 prints / 6 envelopes; 3 framed photographs; 4 albums (Box XX392 - 10.A-V)
  - Photo of International American Conference of Conciliation and Arbitration, Washington D.C.; photo of Marguerite Blake Wilbur, 1929 (Folder mA)
  - Photo of Conference on Illiteracy members, 1929; photo of Ray Lyman Wilbur with unidentified group; photo of unidentified Allied officers and civilians, Berlin, 1919 (Folder mB* dr.1)
  - Framed portrait of Ray Lyman Wilbur, 1931; Framed photo of Heidelberg Castle, Germany. Framed photo of the Forum, Rome (Folder Art rack)
  - 3 photo albums showing the construction of Hoover Dam, 1930-1932 (Folder fC-E)
  - 1 print of Ray L. Wilbur, Stanford, 1906; 1 print of Ray L. Wilbur and others at the Pan-american Union, Washington D.C, 1929; 1 print of Ray L. Wilbur and others at the Pan-american Union, Washington D.C., 1930; 1 print of Ray L. Wilbur and others at the Pan-american Union, Washington D.C, 1932; 1 print of Gertrude Paist Naugler with children; 1 print of Teddy Naugler, 1940 (Folder mF)
  - 6 prints taken at the Honolulu Conference of the Institute of Pacific Relations, 1925 (Folder mG)
    Includes a photograph of Ray Lyman Wilbur, William Allen White and other American Participants.
  - Album of 51 prints of participants in the Honolulu Conference of the Institute of Pacific Relations, 1925 (Folder fH)
  - 1 print of participants in the Yosemite Conference of the Institute of Pacific Relations, 1941 (Folder mB* dr. 1)
  - 2 prints of President Herbert Hoover and his cabinet, 1929-1932; 5 prints of Ray Lyman Wilbur and others at Stanford University functions; 6 prints relating to an illiteracy clinic on the Blackfeet Indian Reservation, circa. 1930; 3 prints and related material of organizers and exhibits at the Craterville Park State Indian Fair, Oklahoma, 1928; One print of Chao-Chu Wu (Chinese Amb. to U.S.) and his wife, Pao-Fung, 1932; 1 print of an unidentified physician, 1 print of the inauguration of Laurence Judd as Gov. of Hawaii, 1929 (Folder mI)
- Wilhelm II, German Emperor Collection, 1859-1941; 6 prints / 2 envelopes, 1 framed photograph (Box XX382 - 10.A-V)
  - 1 photo of Kaiser Wilhelm II with Paul von Hindenburg and Erich Ludendorff during World War I (Folder A)
  - 4 photos of Kaiser Wilhelm II with Theodore Roosevelt in 1910; 1 photo of Kaiser Wilhelm II in Morocco in 1905 (Folder mB dr. 3)
  - 1 framed and autographed portrait of Kaiser Wilhelm II in 1912. Presented to Mayor William Jay Gaynor of New York (Folder 9.cab)
- Williams, Lt. Gen. Samuel T. Collection, 104 prints / 9 envelopes (Box 81032 - 10.A-V)
  - 20 miscellaneous prints, undated (Folder A)
    Includes 9 prints of Father Raymond de Jaegher; 2 prints of Ngo-Dinh-Nhu; and 1 print of Gen. Omar Bradley.
  - 10 portrait prints of Lt. Gen. Samuel T. Williams, 1941-1954 (Folder B)
  - 5 prints depicting lt. Gen. Williams' command in Germany, 1946-1950 (Folder C)
  - 5 prints depicting the 26th Infantry Regiment, undated (Box D)
  - 28 prints depicting Lt. Gen. Williams' command in Korea and Japan, undated (Box E)
    Includes 8 prints of Syngman Rhee and 8 prints of Gen. Maxwell Taylor.
  - 7 prints depicting Lt. Gen. Williams' command at Fort Sam Houston, 1955 (Box F)
  - 16 prints depicting Lt. Gen. Williams as Chief of MAAG, undated (Box G)
    Includes 5 prints of Pres. Ngo-Dinh-Diem; 1 print of Amb. Eldridge Durbrow; 2 prints of Gen. Le-Van-Ty; 1 print of Gen. Duong-Van-Minh (Big Minh); and 2 prints of Sec. Wilbur Brucker.
  - 10 prints of Lt. Gen. Williams' visit to West Point, 1961 (Box H)
  - 3 miscellaneous prints. includes 1 print of Gen. Le-Van-Ty, Maj. Gen. Ton-That_dinh and lt. Gen. Samuel T. Williams, undated (Folder mI)
- Williams (Thomas) Collection, 16 prints / 3 envelopes (Box 74069 - 10 A-V)
  - 8 photos of Herbert Hoover as U.S. Food Administrator as President-elect in front of his Stanford home, as President with cabinet members (autographed by Ray L. Wilbur), and with Lou Henry (autographed), undated (Folder A)
    Includes 4 photos of Lou Henry Hoover, including one with her Stanford classmates.
  - 2 photos of Herbert Hoover with pet dog (Folder mB)
  - 6 photos relating to Camping Trips of the Wooley Camp Association (some photos depicting Herbert Hoover, Dr. Wilbur, etc.) (Folder C)
- Willis, Francis E. Collection, circa 1061 prints / 11 albums, 35 envelopes (Box 84031- - 10.A-V)
- Willoughby, Charles Andrew Collection, undated; 1 envelope, 1 album (Box 61013 - 10.A-V)
  - 2 sheets of reproductions of photographs and drawings of General Charles A. Willoughby; 12 photographs of guests at a dinner given by General Willoughby in honor of Harold H. Fisher, Directory of the Hoover Institution at the Imperial Hotel, Tokyo, Japan, January 23, 1950 (Folder m A)
  - Album of photographs taken by U.S. Army Forces in the Pacific, 1947, of Japanese paintings exhibited at the Ueno Museum, Tokyo depicting scenes of Japanese military and naval forces in action in China and the pacific, 1937-1945 (Folder f B)
- Wilson (Richard C.) Collection, 104 prints and 6 negs / 4 envelopes (Box 72057 - 10 A-V)
  - 24 photos of scenes at Japanese internment camps near Hong Kong, 1941 and 1945 (Folder A)
  - 19 photos of scenes in the Philippines and the staff of the Manila Chronicle, including Richard Wilson and Eugenio Lopez, the publisher, 1948-1953 (Folder B)
  - 48 photos of people appearing in the "Far Easterner", including businessmen such as William P. Hunt, U.S. Banknote Corp.; Howard J. Schlereth, Mahl Petroleum Col. Carl H. Boehringer, American Chamber of Commerce in Japan; and missionaries such as Bishop James E. Walsh, undated (Folder C)
  - 19 photos of Richard Wilson and miscellaneous travel scenes, undated (Box D)
- Wiren, Nicholas Collection, 1919; 1 print / 1 envelope (Box 76115 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  Print of Nicholas Wiren in Russian military uniform.
- Wisner, Lewis S. Collection, May 12, 1864; 1 print, 1 negative / 1 envelope (Box 78044 - 10.A-V)
  1 print of a Civil War drawing by Lewis Wisner's grandfather, Spotsylvania, Virginia. 1 negative - subject unidentified.
- Wisniewski, Tomasz Collection, undated; 26 prints / 1 envelope (Box 90094 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  26 prints of synagogues and scenes of Jewish life, primarily in and around Biaystok, Poland, prior to and during World War II.
- Wittfogel, Karl August Collection, 1704 prints, 4482 negatives, 24 albums, 19 slides / 61 envelopes, 6 album boxes, 1 slide box. (Box 66033 - 10.A-V, 57.05, slide cabinet)
- Wolbert, Louise D. Collection, undated; 1 album (Box 88044 - 8M.02)
  Album of photographs, depicting American troops and entertainers, street scenes and scenes of war damage, in France and elsewhere in western Europe.
- Wolfe, Bernard Collection, 1937; 46 slides / 1 envelope (Box 93086 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  Depicts Leon Trotsky and others at hearings in Coyoacan, Mexico, of the Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials.
- Wolfe, Bertram David Collection, 807 prints, 9 drawings, 6 negatives, 3 color slides, 4 glass plates / 35 envelopes (Box 77029 - 10.A-V)
- Wolfe (Henry C.) Collection, 1920-1923; 42 prints / 1 envelope (Box 77073 - 10.A-V)
  42 photos depicting conditions in the Samara Province of Russia during the operations of the American Relief Administration.
- Woolf, Paul M. Collection, undated; 130 photographs / 2 postcards / 1 envelope (Box 63020 - 10.A-V)
  130 photos and 2 postcards of photographs of Japan in 1906 after the close of the Russo-Japanese war. The majority of the photos depict people, scenic views, military parades, and captured weapons.
- Woronzow-Daschkow (Hilarion) Collection, undated; 158 prints / 3 boxes (Box 76067 - 8M.02)
  - 19 prints from the "Album of the Masquerade ball at the Winter Palace in February 1903" depicting leading members of the Russian Imperial nobility, undated (Folder fA)
  - SAME. 59 prints. Also Kazanskii Sobor, 1811-1911 V SanktPeterburge (The Kazan Cathederal, 1811-1911, in Saint Petersburg), undated (Folder fB)
  - SAME. 80 prints, undated (Folder fC)
- Yeaton, (Ivan D.) Collection, undated; 7 envelopes / 84 photos (Box 76013 - 10 A-V)
  - 1 portrait photo of Ivan D. Yeaton, 1950, and 1 photo of Ivan D. Yeaton receiving the Legion of Merit, undated (Folder A)
  - 9 photos of Ivan D. Yeaton and other members of the 27th Infantry Regiment, A.E.F. Siberia, 1919-1920 (Folder B)
  - 1 photo of Ivan D. Yeaton and other members of a horsemanship class, Fort Sill, 1929 (Folder C)
  - 1 photo of Gen. George Strong presenting Lt. Gen. Filipp R. Golikov, Soviet Union, with the Legion of Merit (see page 33 in Memoris for details), 1941 (Box D)
  - 18 photos of Ivan D. Yeaton as Deputy Commander, Sixth Army, Presidio of San Francisco, and others, undated (Box E)
    Includes 1 photo of Gen. A. C. Wedemeyer congratulating Col. Yeaton at the latter's retirement ceremony.
  - 52 photos of Ivan D. Yeaton, Patrick Hurley, A.C. Wedemeyer, Mao Tse-Tung, Chou En-Lai, Chu Teh, Huang Hua, and others in Yenan, China, 1945-1946 (Box F)
  - 1 photo of Ivan D. Yeaton and others in Shanghai, 1946 (Box G)
- Yelsky, Isadore Collection, undated; 169 prints / 3 envelopes (Box 82006 - 10.A-V)
  - 22 prints of American troops and scenes of everyday life in the Philippines, circa 1918-1920 (Folder A)
  - 147 prints of American and other foreign troops in Siberia during the Russian Revolution and scenes of the Russian Civil War in Siberia, circa 1918-1920 (Folder B-C)
- Young (Arthur N.) Collection, undated; 6 prints / 1 envelope / 2 albums (Box 66005 - 9.23)
  - 6 prints depicting war debt settlement proceedings between the U.S. and Italy, Belgium, Greece, Yugoslavia, and Czechoslovakia. Prints are labeled, 1925-1926
  - 2 albums of 1931 floods in China (shelved on top shelf in Director of Archives' office) One album in English, one in Chinese, undated
- Young Men's Christian Association Collection, undated; 20,000 photos / 123 envelopes and 40 albums (Box 33002 - 10A-V)
  20,000 photos of activities of the Y.M.C.A during World War I in the U.S. and Europe. Includes photos of military camps, hospitals, libraries, social and recreational activities, etc.
- Zaleski, August Collection, undated; 19 prints / 1 envelope (Box 80163 - 10A-V)
  11 prints depicting relatives and friends of August Zaleski, 4 prints depicting the grave of August Zaleski, 2 prints depicting August Zaleski as a Foreign Minister, 1 print depicting Polish War Cemetery, and 1 print depicting Polish Museum.
- Zambia, Ministry of Information and Broadcasting Collection, undated; 2 prints / 1 envelope (Box m80079 - 10.A-V)
  Depicts Zambian and Chinese crews laying track for the Tanzam Railroad, and inauguration ceremonies upon completion of the railroad.
- Zilm, Harvey Collection, 1922; 31 prints / 1 album (Box 92058 - 8.16 Box 1)
  31 prints depicting the U.S. Navy gunboat Sacramento and other foreign ships in Vladivostok harbor, Japanese and Russian troops in Vladivostok, and various locations in Vladivostok.
- Zimmerman, Olver B. Collection, August 1914; 3 prints, 2 negatives / 1 envelope (Box 75031 - 10.A-V)
  3 prints and 2 negatives (one glass) depicting the entrance of the German Army into Brussels, Belgium, taken in from the window of the office of the International Harvester Company by O.B. Zimmerman.
- Zog I. King of Albania Collection, 1961; 1 print / 1 envelope (Box 61004 - 10.)
  1 print, autographed.